wagner.edu 2016-05-31

# Digital Policies - Communications & Marketing

Section I: Policies for web visitors

  1. All content, including text, photographs of people and places, files, and other data on wagner.edu, is either the sole property of Wagner College or used by permission. Web users may not download or otherwise use multimedia content from wagner.edu unless authorized by the College.
  2. Wagner College makes every attempt to keep the information on wagner.edu as accurate and current as possible. However, the College will not be held responsible for out-of-date or inaccurate content.
  3. Wagner College may link to external sites, but does not hold responsibility for the content of those sites. Links to offensive or irrelevant websites will be removed as soon as possible.

Section II: Privacy Policy

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their ‘Personally identifiable information’ (PII) is being used online. PII, as used in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

## What information do we collect?

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your Name, Email address, Mailing address, Phone number or other details to help you with your experience.

## When do we collect information?

We collect information from you when you register on our site, subscribe to a newsletter, respond to a survey, fill out a form or enter information on our site.

## How do we use your information?

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:

  * To personalize user’s experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested.
  * To improve our website in order to better serve you.
  * To allow us to better service you in responding to your customer service requests.
  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature.
  * To send periodic emails regarding your order or other products and services.

## How do we protect visitor information?

We use vulnerability scanning and/or scanning to PCI standards. We also use an SSL certificate.

We implement security measures when a user enters, submits, or accesses their information. We use a payment gateway provider.

## Do we use ‘cookies’?

We use cookies to:

  * Understand and save user’s preferences for future visits,
  * Keep track of advertisements,
  * Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third party services that track this information on our behalf.
  * It won’t affect the users experience

## Third Party Disclosure

We may transfer your non-identifiable information to third parties. We may also transfer your identifiable information, but only to trusted third parties

## Third party links

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

## Google

We have not enabled Google AdSense on our site but we may do so in the future.

## California Online Privacy Protection Act

According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:

  * Users can visit our site anonymously
  * Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page, or as a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website.
  * Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’, and can be easily be found on the page specified above.

Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes on our Privacy Policy Page.  
Users are able to change their personal information by emailing or calling us.

## How does our site handle do not track signals?

We honor them and do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

## Does our site allow third party behavioral tracking?

We allow

## COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)

We do not specifically market to children under 13

## Fair Information Practices

In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices, should a data breach occur within 7 business days, we will notify the users via in site notification within 7 business days.

We agree to the individual redress principle, which requires that individuals have a right to pursue legally enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or a government agency to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors

## Contact Information

Wagner College  
One Campus Road  
Staten Island, NY 10301  
digitalmedia@wagner.edu  
718/420-4468

Section III: Policies for web managers of wagner.edu

All official departments and offices of Wagner College must maintain their primary web presence on wagner.edu, and must use the templates and designs provided or approved by the Office of Communications and Marketing. This ensures consistent design and navigation across the College. Personal Faculty and Student Sites may use different themes, templates, and designs (faculty.wagner.edu and students.wagner.edu); policies and guidelines for those sites are found elsewhere.

### Site Structure

  1. Major departments and offices are contained in the root directory of wagner.edu. For example, wagner.edu/cace and wagner.edu/anthropology. Centers, services, and units that belong to these major offices must be contained in the website of the larger office. For example, the Biological Sciences Department website houses the EM Center, and the Theatre and Speech Department website (wagner.edu/theatre) houses information on the theatre season, the arts administration major, the Stanley Drama Award, and all other programs contained within the department.
  2. URLs should be kept as short as reasonably possible and use hyphens to separate words. For example, wagner.edu/res-ed, not wagner.edu/residential_education.

### Management

  1. Department/Office Responsibilities. Each department and office of Wagner College is responsible for its own web presence, although the Office of Communications and Marketing or Office of Information Technology reserves the right to remove or edit content at any time. The director or chair has responsibility over the content of that area, but may delegate web management to someone else. Each area is responsible for the following: 
    1. Creating and maintaining up-to-date and accurate content related to the area’s personnel and activities. Site content should be reviewed at least once each semester, or as often as necessary to maintain accuracy and relevance of all content, and to ensure that links are accurate and working.
    2. Designating a dedicated point person to manage and edit web content within the area’s website.
    3. Abiding by best practices outlined in these policies and in the online web tutorials.
    4. Attending website training sessions as needed.
  2. User Permissions. 
    1. Top level sites, such as the homepage and “About” section, are managed by the Office of Communications and Marketing.
    2. When a web editor leaves College employment, his or her permission will be immediately removed from the site database by the Office of Information Technology, and all editing permissions will be revoked.
    3. When a web editor leaves the office and dept or changes positions, the editing permissions will be immediately adjusted as appropriate by the manager(s) of that website. Web managers should check their site’s users every semester.
    4. Top-level managers should have “administrator” or “editor” permissions. Student workers should have permissions that expire at the end of their employment. Content published by GAs and other students must be routinely checked by a full-time employee.
    5. All users must use their Wagner College username and password to access the site. A Wagner College All-Access Pass is required for editing wagner.edu, faculty.wagner.edu, or students.wagner.edu.
  3. Top Pages. 
    1. All requests for changes to the homepage, header, footer, “About” pages, Events Calendar, or Newsroom must be submitted to the Office of Communications and Marketing.
    2. Priorities for the homepage are based on the size of the intended audience and the relevance to the College’s top website priorities.
    3. All links from the College homepage must stay on the wagner.edu or wagnerathletics.com domains.

### Content

  1. Keep it fresh. 
    1. Content must be centralized in the correct department or office website. If other websites refer to that information, they must link to the centralized location instead of copying the information. For example, instead of uploading a Campus Map to the Art Department’s site, that site should link to the Campus Map in the centralized Visit Campus section. This keeps all content current and correct.
    2. Content on all subsites must be current and relevant. Outdated information must be updated as soon as possible, or removed if the page is obsolete. The website should be a hub of up-to-date content, not an archive of old material. 
      1. When a page needs updating, instead of creating a new page with the current information and removing the outdated page, the existing page should be updated.
      2. The URLs for those pages should not include dates. This will keep links across wagner.edu working correctly.
      3. For example, the page for ILC courses should be updated at wagner.edu/academics/undergraduate/ilc/courses, NOT wagner.edu/academics/undergraduate/ilc/fall-2012-courses.
    3. Old files in the Media Library must be removed on a regular basis, so they do not appear in search queries.
    4. Links must be checked regularly (at least once a semester) to make sure they are working correctly.
  2. Keep it clean. 
    1. Wagner College will not tolerate offensive or abusive content on wagner.edu or any online platforms. Content that is deemed inappropriate will be removed immediately, and the user responsible for that content will have web permissions revoked. Additional disciplinary actions may occur according to the policies in the employee, faculty and student handbooks.
    2. Copy should be written with the audience in mind, in a positive and friendly manner. Use of second person is acceptable and encouraged. Informal and approachable language, without being overly chatty, welcomes visitors to our site and encourages engagement. Use short sentences and paragraphs of no more than 3-4 sentences, with a full break in between.
    3. Layouts must align with the provided templates, shortcodes, and styles. For example, provided headings must be used instead of an image file of large text.
    4. Video should be embedded via Wagner College’s [YouTube channel](http://youtube.com/wagnercollegenyc).
    5. All copy must conform to high editorial standards, with proper spelling, punctuation, grammar, style, etc.
    6. Do NOT WRITE IN ALL CAPS. EVER.
  3. Keep it accessible. 
    1. All Wagner College web pages must comply with state and federal accessibility standards.
    2. Write meaningful link text.
    3. Include descriptive alt text for photos
  4. Keep it legal. 
    1. When uploading or posting confidential information, web editors must be extremely cautious. PDFs and other files are searchable and not private unless protection is specifically applied.
    2. Wagner College must have copyright ownership or permission for all content, including text, photographs, maps, graphics, files, and other data. Web editors may not upload or publish any content that does not meet copyright criteria. For example, a photograph found with Google search cannot be downloaded and published on wagner.edu without express permission from the photographer or owner of the photograph.

Section IV: Policies for Daily Bulletin email

The Daily Bulletin is Wagner College’s daily email newsletter.

In the very first issue — dated Oct. 12, 2010 — we explained why we were introducing an email newsletter to the campus community: _In response to requests from the Student Government Association for a reduction in the number of emails, we are consolidating as many as possible of the daily administrative notices to the campus community into a single daily bulletin. Feel free to let us know if you feel this helps or hinders campus communications._

The Daily Bulletin consists of just two parts: short notices, and “Today at Wagner.”

The short notices appearing at the top of the Daily Bulletin are items of general interest to the campus community — programs to sign up for, unusual activities on campus that might affect your day, schedules for campus services during holiday breaks, links to Wagner-related news stories, and “Photo of the Day” highlights on the college’s Facebook page. To place a short notice in the Daily Bulletin, [just email Lee Manchester](mailto:lee.manchester@wagner.edu?subject=Short%20notice%20for%20the%20Daily%20Bulletin).

The “Today at Wagner” section at the bottom of the Daily Bulletin consists of a list of campus activities scheduled that day, showing time, location, and a link to event descriptions containing more information, whenever it’s available.

“Today at Wagner” pulls all its information from the college’s [online events calendar](http://wagner.edu/newsroom/events/), which contains information on all scheduled upcoming Wagner events, both on- and off-campus. To find information about upcoming events, visit the [online events calendar](http://wagner.edu/newsroom/events/).

To place events in the [online events calendar](http://wagner.edu/newsroom/events/), just fill in the required information when you book space for your event using the [Ad Astra system](http://wagner.edu/it/training/tutorial-videos/ad-astra-videos/). For help using the calendar, [you can visit our website for a tutorial](http://wagner.edu/communications/web-group/campus-calendar/). For additional information or assistance, [email Caitlin Miller](mailto:caitlin.miller@wagner.edu?subject=Help%20with%20the%20online%20calendar) in our Lifelong Learning office.

 _Updated September 2014_
